<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: papers | jordan-wright]]></title>
  <link href="http://jordan-wright.github.io/blog/categories/papers/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jordan-wright.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-27T06:10:07-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://jordan-wright.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jordan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My (Probably Boring) Research Papers on Security]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordan-wright.github.io/blog/2014/12/02/my-probably-boring-research-papers-on-security/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-02T22:50:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordan-wright.github.io/blog/2014/12/02/my-probably-boring-research-papers-on-security</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/headers/papers.png"/></p>

<h3>Introduction</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;ve always been a proponent and contributor of open-source projects and information. I strongly believe that information and knowledge should be shared as much and as freely as possible &ndash; progress happens this way.</p>

<p>As such, I&rsquo;ve decided to &ldquo;open-source&rdquo;, if you will, the academic essays I wrote regarding information security and software development my last couple of semesters at Texas Tech. It&rsquo;s my hope that people find these useful, either by provoking thought and discussion or simply by serving as material to help people fall asleep a little easier.</p>

<p>Please bear in mind some of these papers were written <del>the night before</del> in a short time-span.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>The Papers</h3>

<p>Here are the papers (in no particular order):</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/y7mz05n47zs71qu/A%20Systems%20Analysis%20of%20the%20Cybercrime%20Industry.pdf?dl=0"><em>A Systems Analysis of the Cybercrime Industry</em></a> &ndash; A formal systems analysis of the current cybercrime industry, showing how this industry is similar to &ldquo;a market for lemons&rdquo;.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/rvk6ybbl85zce00/The%20Fault%20Tolerance%20of%20Botnets.pdf?dl=0"><em>The Fault Tolerance of Botnets</em></a> &ndash; Studying fault tolerant models of botnets</li>
<li><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/jy8v6tmsjyr65z5/The%20State%20of%20Email%20Security.pdf?dl=0"><em>The State of Email Security</em></a> &ndash; A study regarding the history and current state of email threats and subsequent security mitigations.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/db2tbau0jdv9pym/Paradigm%20Exercise.pdf?dl=0"><em>Paradigm Shift in Software Development</em></a> &ndash; A brief look into how the creation and establishment of the OSS movement created a paradigm shift in software development methodologies.</li>
</ul>


<p>As always, let me know if you have any questions or comments below! It is worth noting that I do my best to provide the best attribution possible, but if you find mistakes please let me know and I will correct it immediately.</p>

<p>Enjoy!</p>

<p>Jordan (<a href="http://twitter.com/jw_sec">@jw_sec</a>)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
